Babafemi Ibitolu

Senior Software Engineer

No1, Emmanuel Ibitolu street, off Addo road, Ajah, Lagos, Nigeria

+2348122310370 | femi.ibitolu@yahoo.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate and enthusiastic software developer with some commercial experience, and also experience using cutting-edge development tools, articulate in professional communication skills. Productive in both team based and self-managed project. Ability to think through problems. Vast knowledge in C#, .NET, and T-SQL with database design. Experience in full life-cycle of software development process including requirement gathering, design, coding, testing, debugging and maintenance.

Strong written and verbal communications. Interested in a challenging technical track career in an application development environment.

TECHNOLOGIES

Front End	Html 5, CSS, Angular 2+, Bootstrap, Blazor
Back End	Asp .Net Core, Asp.Net MVC
Programming Languages	C#, Node.js
Data Stores	MongoDB, MySQL, SQLite, SQL Server
Mobile Frameworks	Xamarin
Agile Tools	Azure Devops, TFS
Testing tools	Moq, Selenium, xUnit
ORM	Dapper, Entity framework / Entity framework Core, RepoDb
DevOps	Docker, CICD, Azure DevOps
Design Patters	Solid and some of the other 26, DDD, CQRS
Architecture	Clean architecture, Micro services, N-tier, SOA, DDD
Messaging (AMQP)	RabbitMq (masstransit), NServicebus

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineering | Rexelpay | Lagos, Nigeria

February 2021 – present

- Lead and manage the Software Development teams to deliver software that meets business requirements.
- Deliver software projects on time and without supervision.
- Mentor other software teams.

- o Lead and manage the Software Development teams to deliver software meets business requirements.
- o Ensured delivery consistent with Agile processes across team.
- Worked effectively with Product Managers and Product Owners to ensure delivery against agreed priorities.
- Created, implemented and maintained a continuous improvement plan for software development.
- Reviewed and applied best practices consistent with those established by Software Centre of Excellence regarding architecture and frameworks consistent with and supportive of the Product Strategy.
- Ensured that technology standards and best practices are maintained across the software development groups.
- O Drove consistent standards and approaches throughout the development teams.

Senior Software Developer | Longbridge Tech (Team Lead, Heritage Bank) | Lagos, Nigeria March 2019 – July 2020

Longbridge Technologies is a technology firm that provides technology services to varying clients using cutting edge technologies and most sorted after software professionals

- O Designed and implement a central administrative portal, which manages single sign on for the bank, manages roles, permissions and audit log for all the banks internal facing applications.
- o Implemented a project called SANEF (share agent network expansion facility). A project that allows those in the rural area to operate banking like they were in the cities. Powered by the central bank of Nigeria.
- o Implemented the banks CI/DI pipeline using AzureDevOps.
- o Ensure all my team mates implemented integration, unit test at the minimum.
- o Integration with Bet9ja, Premier Lotto, USSD.
- o Implemented a workflow engine for account opening process.
- o Implemented a workflow engine for booking of term deposit and liquidation of term deposit.
- o Ensured I refactored my codes and my teammates codes on a regular basis.
- o Managed a team of 6 developers to ensure timely delivery of projects.
- Was a mentor to my team mate's and gave support to everybody's software to ensure the success of all.
- o Performed code review weekly with my team mates.
- o Integration to Finnacle via Finnacle integrator.

Technologies: ASP.Net Core, C#, SQL Server, Mongo Db

Software Architect | Webafriq Technologies | Lagos, Nigeria

March 2017 - Present

Webafriq is a technology firm that provides technology services to clients from all sectors, focusing on clients' needs and customizing solution for them.

- O Designed, implement and built a real estate / housing industry ecosystem application. That brings every single player in the housing space on one platform. It is like a market place for every single player in that space. From the home buyer, to mortgage, to investor, to all kinds of financial institutions, developers etc.
- O Designed and build a core banking application. That handles modules like, account opening, general ledger management, loan management, fixed asset management etc.
- o Managed a team of four developers.
- o Implemented CI/DI pipeline using AzureDevOps.
- Ensure all my team mates implemented integration, unit test at the minimum.
 Ensured I refactored my codes and my teammates codes on a regular basis.
- Was a mentor to my team mate's and gave support to everybody's software to ensure the success of all.
- o Performed code review weekly with my team mates.

<u>Technologies</u>: ASP.Net Core, Masstransit over RabbitMq, C#, Azure DevOps, SQL Server, MongoDb, Moq, XUnit, Angular2+, angular, Micro services, DDD, EntityframeworkCore, Akka.Net

Group Head Technology, Retail Banking Cloud | Appzone | Lagos, Nigeria Jan 2015 – Dec 2016 Appzone Ltd. One of Africa foremost financial technology companies, that render fintech services to financial institutions.

- o I created solutions architecture, algorithms, and designs for solutions that scale to the customers', business requirements.
- Leads designing and coding of critical system components in accordance with the established coding standards and guidelines.

o Managed and supported Appzone flagship product, BANKONE.

Software Developer | FCMB | Lagos, Nigeria One of Nigeria most reputable banks.

Feb 2014 – Dec 2014

- o Designed and developed the banks central store management system.
- o Designed and developed a developer tracker system.
- o Interface with business team to define system requirements and/or necessary modifications.
- Regularly implemented TDD, unit testing, mocking, integration/UI testing and behavior driver testing.

Software Developer | Nigerian Development Foundation | Lagos, Nigeria A private human and National development organization.

Mar 2013 - Feb 2014

- o I maintained and developed the full software lifecycle of the wealth market software backend.
- Built the backend of the wealth market software and interact with existing financial application written in java and MySQL.

Software Developer | Webafriq | Lagos, Nigeria

Jun 2010 - March 2013

Webafriq is a technology firm that provides technology services to clients from all sectors, focusing on clients' needs and customizing solution for them.

- o I was an instructor on C#, asp.net, windows forms, SQL, JQuery.
- Built websites for some hospitality clients.
- o Built a school portal that managed the administrative and parent's activities.

EDUCATION

B.sc Sociology | University of Ilorin | Ilorin, Kwara State, Nigeria

2002 - **2007**

CERTIFICATIONS

Secure Coding | Mapp Technologies & services Ltd

2019

REFEREES

Name: Mr Ifeanyi Aneke

Email: Ifeanyi.aneke@outlook.com

Tel:08090928111

Name: Efe Ekunbo

Email: fredaconcept@gmail.com

Tel: 07034625487